Preliminary Guide to the Park-Lambuth-Sherertz family papers, 1825-1989 RL.00995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Park-Lambuth-Sherertz family papers
1825-1989
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Park family
RL.00995
2.5 Linear Feet
The Park, Lambuth, and Sherertz families were Methodist missionaries to China, Japan, and Africa. The collection includes the family Bible; correspondence to and from members of the three families; reports; diary entries; genealogical information; a videocassette; photographs; printed material; poetry; and typescripts of essays regarding family members' daily lives and work as missionaries in China, Japan, and Africa. The families mentioned are ancestors of Olive Sherertz Lanham (Duke '43). Materials range in date from circa 1825 to 1989.
1000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Some of the materials in this collection may not be immediately accessible because they require further processing before use. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Park-Lambuth-Sherertz family papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001, 2002, and 2004.
Biographical Note
The Park, Lambuth, and Sherertz families were Methodist missionaries to China, Japan, and Africa.
Collection Overview
The collection (01-108) (160 items, 1.2 linear feet; dated 1825-1970s) includes the family Bible; correspondence to and from members of the three families; graphic materials; printed material; poetry; and typescripts of essays regarding family members' daily lives and work as missionaries in China, Japan, and Africa. The families mentioned are ancestors of Olive Sherertz Lanham (Duke '43). Includes 2 color prints, 5 black-and-white prints, and 2 albumen prints.
The addition (01-146) (375 items, .6 linear feet; dated 1898-1977) contains letters; reports; diary entries; genealogical information; 1 videocassette; 2 black-and-white photographs, 1 black-and-white print, and 1 albumen print. There are also other items, chiefly relating to the Park, Lambuth, and Sherertz families' life and work in China and Japan.
The 2002 addition (02-179) (100 items, .2 lin. ft.; dated 1825-1981 and n.d.) consists primarily of memoirs and correspondence documenting the families' ancestry and experiences in China and Japan (1825-1981 and n.d.). Also includes newspaper clippings about family members.
The 2004 addition (07-080) (375 items, 0.6 lin. ft; dated circa 1890-1989 and undated) contains letters, biographical sketches of family members, clippings, writings, and photographs documenting the members of the Park, Lambuth, and Sherertz families. Materials range in date from circa 1890 to 1989.
Christian education -- Japan -- History; Christian education -- China -- History; Black-and-white prints (photographs); Albumen prints; Black-and-white negatives; Missionaries; Missionaries -- Africa; Missionaries -- China; Color prints (photographs); Missionaries -- Japan; Methodists -- Missions -- Africa -- History; Videocassettes; Methodists -- Missions -- China -- History; Methodists -- Missions -- Japan -- History; Christian education -- Africa -- History; Park family; Sherertz family; Lambuth family
- Accessions 2001-0108 and 2001-0146, 3 boxes
  - Contents of box 1: (Box 1)
    - The Lambuth Letters, 1827-1949 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and poetry, 1902-1949, 1970s (Box 1)
    - Photographs, including albumen prints (Box 1)
    - University Unique, by Dwight Lamar Sherertz (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Description of Sherertz's experience working in Pootung University in a Japanese internment camp, ca. 1940
    - The Contribution of Christian Missions to Women and Children of Rural Areas to China, term paper by Dwight Lamar Sherertz, 1945 April 28 (Box 1)
    - Report of Women's Work at Old Umtall, Rhodesia Conf., Africa, by Rita Park Sherertz, 1953 December 1 (Box 1)
    - Report of the Soochow Hospital, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Contents of box 2: (Box 2)
    - Family Bible, 1854 (Box 2)
      Includes record of births (1830-1889 and 1858-1951), marriages (1853-1919 and 1943-1964), and deaths (1863-1965).
  - Contents of box 3: (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, 1881-1977 (Box 3)
    - A history of the Lambuth family, family stories, journal entries, and other genealogical material (Box 3)
    - Bibliography of materials relating to Walter Russell Lambuth and paper about Walter Russell Lambuth by W. E. Towson (Box 3)
    - The Lambuth Family and Kwansei Gakuin, by Frances H. Bray (Box 3)
    - The Story of the Seventy Dolls (Box 3)
    - Grandma Park's Last Two Years [Nora Lambuth Park] (Box 3)
    - The Role of Japan in the Modern World by Edwin O. Reischauer (Box 3)
    - From Pearl River to the End of the Earth, videocassette tape regarding the Lambuth family, 1980 (Box 3)
      - Digital preservation file (Digital-materials RL00995-SET-0001.mov, Video-file RL00995-VHS-0001.mov)
- Addition, 2002 (2002-0179), 1 boxes
  Addition (02-179) (100 items, .2 lin. ft.; dated 1825-1981 and n.d.) consists primarily of memoirs and correspondence documenting the families' ancestry and experiences in China and Japan (1825-1981 and n.d.). Also includes newspaper clippings about family members.
- Addition, 2004 (2007-0080), 1 boxes
  The 2004 addition (07-080) (375 items, 0.6 lin. ft; dated circa 1890-1989 and undated) contains letters, biographical sketches of family members, clippings, writings, and photographs documenting the members of the Park, Lambuth, and Sherertz families. Materials range in date from circa 1890 to 1989.
  - Memoirs of Dr. W. H. Park of Soochow, 1882-1927, circa 1936 (Box 3)
  - Letters, 1882-1947 (Box 3)
  - This is your life -- Margarita Mary Park Sherertz, biographical sketch with photographs, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Just Talking, by Dwight Lamar Sherertz, August 16, 1937-1946, Typed, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Letters and articles, including some photocopies and typescripts, circa 1947-1989 and undated (Box 3)
  - Poetry, notes, biographical information, undated (Box 3)
  - Clippings, letters, biographical information, 1927-1969 and undated (Box 3)
  - Writings, 1950s-1960s and undated (Box 3)
  - Letters and writings, circa 1940s (Box 3)
  - Letters, 1860 and 1919 (Box 3)
  - My Mother: An Appreciation by Margarita Park Sherertz, undated (Box 3)
  - Writings by Dwight Lamar Sherertz, 1960s and undated (Box 3)
  - Lamar's letters, "old" (Box 3)
  - Clippings (photocopies), 1890s and undated (Box 3)